ISAIAH FRANCOIS

FULL STACK ENGINEER

- francoiscoding.com
- **** 3529893703
- **♀** Clermont, Fl
- in francoiscoding
- FrancoisCoding

A software development and performance engineering expert with 2+ years of experience in developing quality assured applications and supervising/training students. A collaborative developer and engineer with experience and education in the hardware and software sides of technology who thrives on discovery and accelerating performance.

Skills

PROGRAMMING TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript

Python

C#

ReactJS

Express

Git

SQL Redux

SASS

MongoDB

Cypress Testing

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Technical Troubleshooting and Debugging

Software and Engineering Documentation

Systems Architecture and Operations

Teamwork and Crossfunctional Communication

Performance Engineering

Projects

CoachMe Health - https://app.coachmehealth.org/register

Patient first non-profit organization dedicated to improving the health of low-income Americans with diabetes and heart disease with health coaching for those who need it most.

ReactJS | Redux | SASS | Twillio | Cron Jobs | ChartJS | Cypress

- Collaborated remotely with a team of 7 Web Developers and 2 UX/UI Designers to build a fully functional web application over the course of 8 weeks.
- Utilized Twilio's API alongside Cron Jobs to schedule messages to be sent to clients on the backend (Node.js) in order to communicate with users efficiently.

React Movies - https://reactmovies-rmdb.netlify.com/

An IMDB style real world Web Application in ReactJS. Solo project that provides up to date movie information and details.

ReactJS | Bootstrap

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can view information on over 10,000 of the latest movies released.
- Utilized The Movie Database API in order to display all information about latest movie titles to users.

Francois Games - https://francois-game-center.netlify.com/

Solo project that provides up to date game information and details.

ReactJS | Bootstrap | Material UI | Styled-Components

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can view over 300,000 game titles.
- Utilized the RAWG Video Games Database API in order to display all information about latest video game titles to users.

Employment

Lambda School

Team Lead

https://lambdaschool.com/ Nov. 2019 to Current

- Mentored 10+ students on how to learn effectively and solve programming problems.
- Provided daily feedback and issue resolution of all curriculum through Slack interface.
- Led daily standup meetings to build camaraderie, facilitate sharing of ideas and work progress, and provide guidance for that week's study material.
- Delivered one-on-one feedback and code review on a weekly basis, giving feedback on areas of improvement.

CoachMe Health

Full Stack Engineer

https://www.coachmehealth.org/ Oct. 2019 to Dec. 2019

- Developed and maintained system design documents (e.g. proofs of concept, requirements specification, subsystems) and collaborated with project managers to scope milestones, resource use, and report to clients on project progress.
- Collaborated cross-functionally with clients and hardware engineers during the development and integration project phases to troubleshoot and/or debug software stacks.
- Converted requirements from clients into production ready APIs that enabled customization and streamlined work progress.
- Interfaced with development engineers to develop test cases, diagnose problems, and develop debugging methodologies.

Education

Full Stack Web Development, Lambda School · May 2019 to Feb. 2020

Remote